

HARISHANKAR GUPTA

Technical Lead

About Me

Technical Lead with deep knowledge and 12 years of experience in System Design, Data Structure & Algorithms, Design Patterns, Java, MuleSoft, AWS, Spring Boot, Rest API Development, SQL, Microservices. Conversant with various phases of Agile software development, BDD, business requirement analysis, UAT, deployment among the various environments. Involved in Technical & Functional solution, Team management,

Resource utilization.

My Contact



harshaiet22@gmail.com



+91-9818605589



Noida,India



https://www.linkedin.com/in/harishankar-gupta-

- **Skills**
- System Design HIDIID
- RestAPI
- GIT,SVN
- Data Structure & Algorithms
- Design Patterns
- JAVA
- Spring Boot AWS
- MuleSoft
- MicroServices
- Oracle,PostgreSQL
- Hibernate/JPA
- Angular Node Is
- lenkins
- Wildfly/Tomcat

Certification

2021 - 2023 | Mulesoft Developer

Education Background

- B.Tech in computer science from A.I.E.T, Alwar (Affiliated to RTU .Kota) in 2011.
- XII from Rajasthan Board, Ajmer in 2006.
- X from Rajasthan Board, Ajmer in 2004.

Professional Experience

iBoss Techsolutions Pvt. Ltd. | Technical Lead

2019 - 2024

• PWA - PWA, it is a Progressive Web Application system for Contract & Claim management for Dealers for Vehicle Insurance. PWA is platform for dealer with new edge technology and provides magnificent experience to user.

> Tools & Technology: JDK 11, Spring Boot, Microservices, AWS, JPA, RESTful Web Service, JUnit, GITHUB, DevOps, Angular

Role: Maintaining Project Quality, and working Agile Methodology, Interacting with the client on queries regarding the functionality, impact. Task Monitoring and Delegation within the

Tech Mahindra Ltd. | Senior Software Engineer 2016 - 2018 Projects:

ALDB - ALDB allows users to use a user interface to create and update alarm configuration requests. The requests will be edited and confirmed and request identifier to track the request.

Tools & Technology: JDK 1.7, JSP, Ajax, jQuery, Spring 4, Hibernate 4,

RESTful Web Service, JUnit, Jenkins, DevOps.

Role: Maintaining Project Quality, and working Agile Methodology, Interacting with the client on queries regarding the functionality, impact. Task Monitoring and Delegation within the group.

iBoss Techsolutions Pvt. Ltd. | Software Engineer 2014 - 2016 Projects:

. EVAL - EVAL is enterprise validation gateway. It would be used when any contract going to be post, basically it is having set of rules at Enterprise level and OEM level.

> Tools & Technology: JDK 1.8, Angular 7, Spring Boot, Spring Security (JWT), JPA, RESTful Web Service, JUnit, Go Pipeline, DevOps

> > Role: Developing and Maintaining Project Quality and working in Agile Methodology, Interacting with the client on queries regarding the functionality, impact. Task Monitoring and Delegation within the group.

FSL Software Technologies Ltd. | Software Engineer 2011 - 2014 Projects:

• SalesMantra CRM- Sales Mantra helps to manage relationship with the customers and improve the business and keep the track record of sales and service executives. It has two main modules, Sales and Service.

Tools & Technology: JSP, Servlet, Struts 2.0, Ajax ,jQuery, Display Tag .

Role: Coding of the application on Module basis, Coordinate efforts for completing activities in plan, Analysis of Functional and System requirement.